# Hans J Schroeder Full Stack Developer

Portland, OR/Remote (925)-209-7667 <u>hajschroeder@gmail.com</u> <u>https://hansjschroeder.com/</u>

## **SKILLS**

I am a highly motivated and project-oriented problem solver who is proficient and experienced in React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, CSS, OOP, Functional Programming, TDD (Jest, RSpec), API creation and implementation, Data Structures, Firebase/Firestore, and Git/GitHub. With over fifteen years professional experience, I bring with me a set of soft skills than cannot be overstated

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Opine School, Seattle** - Software Engineer Intern

NOVEMBER 2022-FEBRUARY 2023

- Worked within a **ticket-based** structure to build out **new React components** for application from scratch. This was done both **independently** as well as through **pair programming**.
- Worked across the entire codebase to **fix bugs** within pre-existing components.
- Simplified UI/UX to make it more streamlined and intuitive.
- Collaborated with entire dev team to **test** out new features and products

# **United States Postal Service, Portland, OR** - City Letter Carrier

SEPTEMBER 2016-AUGUST 2021

- Delivered mail and packages to thousands of postal customers.
- Handled sensitive customer information, and maintained important route information such as forwards and mail holds.
- Prioritized safety while meeting and exceeding management's expectations of efficient delivery.

## Public Bikes, San Francisco, CA - Lead Mechanic

**APRIL 2013-JUNE 2016** 

- Handled the intake and scheduling of all customer build and repair tickets.
- Ordered and received all parts and bikes for shop inventory
- As a team leader within a start-up, I focused on providing exceptional customer satisfaction while
  fostering a safe and open environment for staff to feel empowered as individuals, thus increasing
  overall team productivity.

## **EDUCATION**

**Epicodus** - Certificate in Mobile and Web Development

OCTOBER 2021-NOVEMBER 2022

Epicodus focuses on teaching the best coding practices possible, shaping individuals into programmers who are ready to meet industry standards and conventions. We also learned valuable self-teaching skills, as well as how to be effective collaborators.

#### **PROJECTS**